(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T00:46:04.103898",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Step into Dreams
大空スバル 3周記念ライブ「ふれんどあーす！」
Oozora Subaru 3rd Anniversary Live: Friend Earth!
3周年ありがとう！これからもずっと君と一緒に！
Thank you for the 3rd anniversary! I want to be with you forever!
ホロライブに入る！！
I will join Hololive!!
オーディション会場
Audition Venue
あぁ
Ah...
いつものように
Just like always,
過ぎる日々に あくびが出る
I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜 超え今日も
Crossing the bustling night, today again,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning falls on the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち
Somehow feeling empty, that kind of feeling...
つまらないな でもそれでいい
It's boring, but that's fine.
そんなもんさ これでいい
That's just how it is. This is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
The real voice that I had been hiding,
本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
unconsciously, let it resonate, look!
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこにある
it is certainly there.
あぁ
Ah...
感じたままに描く
Drawing just as I feel,
自分で選んだその色で
with the color that I chose myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning clad in drowsy air,
訪れた青い世界
a blue world has arrived.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying that I like what I like,
怖くて仕方ないけど
it's so scary I can't help it, but...
本当の自分 出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I was able to meet my true self.
あぁ
Ah...
手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
The more I reach out my hand,
遠くへゆく
the further away it goes.
思うようにいかない今日も
Even today, when things don't go as planned,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I'm struggling busily again.
悔しい気持ちも
Even these frustrating feelings,
ただ情けなくて涙が出る
just make me feel miserable and cry.
踏み込むほどに 苦しくなる
The more I step forward, the harder it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more it hurts.
あぁ
Ah...
感じたままに進む
Moving forward just as I feel,
自分で選んだこの道を
on this path that I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
On the night when I rub my heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
the blue vow I clung onto.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love,
それは楽しいだけじゃない
isn't just fun all the time.
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど<
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but...
あぁ 何枚でも
Ah, no matter how many pages...
ほら 何枚でも
Look, no matter how many pages...
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I've drawn because I lacked confidence!
あぁ 何回でも
Ah, no matter how many times...
ほら 何回でも
Look, no matter how many times...
何回でも 積み上げてきたことが武器になる
Everything I've built up, time and time again, will become my weapon.
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
Even if I look around, even if I compare myself to others,
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is the one thing that only I can do?
今でも自信なんか無い それでも
Even now, I don't have any confidence, but still...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い
Feelings I've never felt before, emotions I never knew existed,
あの日踏み出して 初めて感じたこの痛みの全部
ever since I took that step that day, even all of this pain I felt for the first time...
好きなものと向き合うことで 触れたまだ小さな光
By facing what I love, I touched a light that is still small.
大丈夫 行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy it.
ああ すべてをかけて描く 自分にしか出せない色で
Ah, I'll paint with everything I've got, in a color only I can produce.
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
Running through both morning and night, the blue light I finally found.
好きなものと向き合うこと 今だって怖いことだけど<,s:
Facing what I love is still a scary thing, even now, but...
もう今は あの日の透明な僕じゃない
I am no longer the invisible me of that day.
ありのままの かけがえのない僕だ
I am my irreplaceable, true self.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ ほら<,s:
Let the real voice you've been unconsciously hiding resound, look!
見ないふりしていても 確かにそこに 今もそこに あるよ
Even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely there, still there.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ さあ
Let the real voice you've been unconsciously hiding resound, come on!
見ないふりしていても 確かにそこに 君の中に
Even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely there, inside of you.
Ah ah ah ah ah ah
駄目駄目駄目駄目駄目の脳味噌の中から
From deep inside my useless brain,
やめろ馬鹿と喚くモラリティ
"Stop it, you idiot!" hollers my morality.
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darlin', baby darlin'
半端なくラブ
Super-duper love
きらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
I'm so excited, out goes my philosophy
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
Death-level kawaii, puppy-dog eyes
何がし法に触れるくらい
You're not illegal? That's a lie
バラ撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Throw money like crazy, my bank is empty
この世に生まれた君が悪い
All because you came into this world that I'm in
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
I'm feeling so weak being love-sick
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
My head and body are scattered all over the place
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
Out of my neck veins, "I love you" shoots out and...
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
一体どうしようこの想いを
But I don't know, what am I feeling?
どうしようあばらの奥を
Don't know what is inside of me
ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
Sugar melts away and turns into a sea of puke
瞳孔バチ開きで溺れ死にそう
Uh-oh, eyes are trippin', I think I'll drown and die
今この世で君だけ大正解
You're the one and only answer in this world that's right
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン
Darlin', darlin', darlin', darlin'
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
No way in hell I'll win this game
君だけルールは適用外
You don't need a rulebook, you're exempt
四つともオセロは黒しかない
All four corners, flipped to black
カツアゲ放題
Take everything I have
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
You had a smile when you fired the "Avada Kedavra"
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
Scar-headed stigma, I'm so sorry, mama
矢を刺して貫いて ここ弱点
Shoot an arrow all the way through, it's my weak spot
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
Death-level kawaii, puppy-dog eyes
何がし法に触れるくらい
You're not illegal? That's a lie
バラ撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Throw money like crazy, my bank is empty
この世に生まれた君が悪い
All because you came into this world that I'm in
パチモンでもいい何でもいい
Don't mind a rip-off, copies and all
今君と名付けてる全て欲しい
Want everything that's out there with your name on it
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
Out of my neck veins, "I love you" shoots out and...
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
一体どうしようこの想いを
But I don't know, what am I feeling?
どうしようあばらの奥を
Don't know what is inside of me
ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
Sugar melts away and turns into a sea of puke
瞳孔バチ開きで溺れ死にそう
Uh-oh, eyes are trippin', I think I'll drown and die
今この世で君だけ大正解
You're the one and only answer in this world that's right
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン
Darlin', darlin', darlin', darlin'
La la la
しゅぴしゅわー！
Shupishuwa!
かなでの充電足りてる？
Are you fully charged with Kanade?
ホロライブ DEV_IS ReGLOSSのノイジーな天然担当
Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's noisy, airheaded member,
音乃瀬奏でーす！
Otohose Kanade here!
ということで 『STEP INTO DREAMS』始まりましたー！
And with that, "STEP INTO DREAMS" has officially begun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
今回はですね オープニングにもあった通り
This time, just like you saw in the opening,
夢だったホロライブに入って
after joining my dream group Hololive,
夢だった初めてのソロステ...
it's my very first dream solo sta...
生誕ライブ3D、いぇーい！
My Birthday 3D Live, yay!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃに緊張しているんですけれども、
I'm actually incredibly nervous right now, but...
どうだった？『群青』と『アイズアウト』
how was it? "Gunjou" and "Eyes Out"?
コメント欄どうだった？カッコよかった？
How was the comment section? Was it cool?
カッコよかったって、きっとまあ、この後流れるんだろうな。カッコよかっただろ？
You probably said it was cool... Well, I'm sure those comments will show up later. It was cool, right?
いっぱい褒めてください。今回はですね、
Please shower me with compliments! This time,
タイトルにもある通り、
just like the title says,
ステップがもうはちゃめちゃに、もうステップが、ステップが、もうはちゃめちゃに多かったりですね、
there were so many crazy steps... There were tons of steps!
あとは、やったことのない
And also,
ジャンルのダンスにも、挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、
I challenged myself with a dance genre I've never tried before,
お楽しみに！
so look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにある
The hashtag is the one shown here:
#水美亜生誕祭2026 です！
#MizumiyaBirthday2026!
スクショとか、感想とかたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you posted lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せトレンド！
Let's aim for trending!
みんな、いっぱい撮ってね。
Everyone, take lots of screenshots!
この後はですね、ゲストパートにも行きたいと思っているのですが、
After this, I'm planning to move on to the guest part, but...
なんと！お祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、
what do you know! It seems we've received a congratulatory video,
見てみましょう！
so let's check it out!
こっちかな？よし。
Is it over here? Alright.
なんだなんだ？
What is it? What is it?
みなさまにごーさいん！志摩市民そして志摩スペイン村のPR大使、
A go-sign for everyone! Shima resident and PR Ambassador for Shima Spain Village,
にじさんじ所属、世怜音女学院、周央サンゴだよー！
Nijisanji's Suo Sango from Seryene Girls' Academy!
水美亜！
Mizumiya!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
きっと今、水美亜は最高のライブをしていることでしょーう！
I'm sure right now, Mizumiya is putting on the best live performance ever!
本当におめでとう！
Happy birthday, truly!
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、
Honestly, I really wanted to celebrate with you directly on-site,
どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、
but our schedules just didn't work out.
お祝いのメッセージ動画をね、今回送らせていただいております。
So I'm sending you this congratulatory message video instead!
水美亜とはね、ロロメロとして、もうたくさんコラボして、
As Lolomelo, Mizumiya and I have done so many collabs together,
プライベートとかでも、テーマパーク行ったりとか、
and in private, we've gone to theme parks,
映画も行ったりとか、
gone to movies,
先日でお泊まりするくらいの、
and even had sleepovers recently.
仲良くね、させてもらってて、
We've become so close,
本当にいつもありがとう！
and really, thank you for everything as always!
事務所がね、違うのにも、こんなに仲良くなれるなんて、
Even though we're from different agencies, being able to get this close
もう、めっちゃ嬉しいし、いつも水美亜に元気もらって、支えてもらってます。
makes me so incredibly happy. You always cheer me up and support me, Mizumiya.
これからも、ずっと友達！
Let's be friends forever!
いっぱい遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうね。
Let's hang out a lot and do tons of fun things together.
大好きだよ！
I love you!
それでは、周央サンゴでした！この後もライブ楽しんでね、がんばれ！
Well then, this was Suo Sango! Keep enjoying your live show, you've got this!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということで、周央サンゴからメッセージが来ました！
And so, I got a message from Suo Sango!
ありがとう、ンゴちゃん！
Thank you, Ngo-chan!
ンゴちゃん、こっちにいるかな？ありがとう、ンゴちゃん！
Ngo-chan, are you over there? Thank you, Ngo-chan!
いやー、そう、今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、
Yeah, that's right, our schedules didn't match up this time,
ンゴちゃんの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって、一緒に踊ったんですけど、
but I was invited to Ngo-chan's 3D live, and we danced together back then.
すうのライブでは、今回は踊れなかったけど、
We couldn't dance together in my live show this time,
いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな！
but let's dance together again someday!
ありがとうね、ンゴちゃん！水美亜がんばるよ！
Thank you, Ngo-chan! Mizumiya will do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲にいこうかな？
Now that I've got her support, shall we move on to the next song?
ちょっと次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
Next up is the guest part, so I wonder who's coming?
この後もまだまだ続きます！
There's still plenty more to come!
そして何か、告知もあるかもしれないので、
And there might be some announcements too,
最後まで楽しんでね！
so please enjoy until the very end!
昔々のそのまた昔
Once upon a time, yes, a very long time ago...
とある貴族の仲良しな兄弟
...lived a certain noble family's close siblings.
（以下略称）
(And so on...)
ちゃんとやれ！
Do it right!
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
The butler calls us to our seats, get ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで 応戦いたしますの
We shall fight back with our knives and forks!
だって僕らは ブルジョアの
Because we are bourgeois,
立派な 立派な 貴族様なんですですの
and we are very, very grand nobles, you see!
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Bow down, peasants! We'll show you the difference between us, vice-vice-royally!
おい待て待て 待て待て 勝手にそんな
Hey, wait, wait! Wait, wait! Doing whatever you want again,
見抜けるような ハッタリかまして
pulling a bluff that anyone can see right through!
はーい はーい はい はい お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Yes, yes, right, right! Just as my dear brother commands (lol).
あーむかつくぜ！ まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so annoying! Seriously, so annoying!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
Showing such an insolent attitude toward your brother!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Cry out the battle cry! Let the gong ring!
ケンカ勃発で 宣戦布告
A fight breaks out, declaring war!
イタズラして 悪ノリして
Playing pranks and getting carried away,
ほら ほら 煽ってくstyleで
look, look, we're provoking you in style!
“大安売り” 買っちゃったら
If you buy into this "special bargain sale,"
毎度ありがとうで 君の負け！
thank you as always for your business, you lose!
狙い引き出しと 煽りあいの駆け引きでキメる
I'll win with a calculated draw and provoking tactics!
兄の威厳 見せるため飴と飴 火花散る チル 両者の目と目
To show my brotherly dignity: a carrot and a carrot / Sparks fly between our eyes.
俺を誰だと思ってる くらえ！おれさまがルールブック
Who do you think I am? Take this! I am the rulebook!
へたれじゃない ひよってない ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ
I'm not a wimp, I'm not chickening out / I'm just lacking a bit of courage!
さぁさぁみなさん お手を拝借
Now, now, everyone, please lend us your hands!
当たり前だろ 余裕しゃくしゃく 生まれながらにして チート
It's only natural, I'm completely at ease / Born with built-in cheats!
やべぇ煌めく 人生がスタート
Oh my, my sparkling life starts now!
当然です見てみな由緒はガチ勢
Obviously, look at my bloodline, it's the real deal!
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破 もらってくぜvサイン
Yes, refuted! Yes, refuted! Yes, refuted! / I'll take that victory sign!
はーい はい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
はなまるよくできました
You did very well!
あーむかつくぜ！ まーむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so annoying! Man, it's so annoying!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Talking back to me like that
とっておきをきみに見舞え
I'll show you my best shot
報復！制裁！挑発しちゃって
Retaliation! Sanctions! Go ahead and provoke!
意地悪して 一枚上手
Playing mean, staying one step ahead
チャンスは貰ってく
I'm taking this chance
ダンスで痛恨ミス！
Making a critical mistake in dance!
あっちゃっちゃー
Oops!
おあいにく様だね君の負け
Unlucky you, it's your loss!
Yes!
だけどキミ キミだけが
But you, only you...
やぁっ！とうっ！やぁっ！うっ！やぁっ！はっ！
Ya! Tou! Ya! Uh! Ya! Ha!
ボクに似合いのライバル！
Are the perfect rival for me!
やぁっ！とうっ！やぁっ！うっ！やぁっ！はっ！
Ya! Tou! Ya! Uh! Ya! Ha!
落ちるのも凹んでんのも
Getting down, feeling depressed,
うっ！はっ！やぁっ！やぁっ！ていっ！はっ！
Uh! Ha! Ya! Ya! Tei! Ha!
調子狂わされるから
Because it throws me off balance,
今宵もてめーと
tonight again with you,
やいやいやいやい
Yai yai yai yai!
大体いつもそうやって我が儘言うから...
You always act so selfishly like that...
ハイ決定！
Okay, decided!
あーむかつくぜ！ まーむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so annoying! Man, it's so annoying!
憎まれ口叩くお口をチャック
Zip up that mouth that speaks such spite
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Shout the battle cry, ring the gong
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ！
The next-generation emperor is me!
悪戯して わるのりして
Playing pranks, taking things too far
ほらほら煽っていくスタイルで
Look, look! That's my provoking style!
1から100 いただきます
I'll take everything from 1 to 100!
毎度ありがとうございました君の...
Thank you as always, you...
まさかの 引き分け！？
No way, a tie?!
えーーっ！？
What?!
この頃君が纏う 躾直しの季節の匂い
The scent of the season of "re-education" that you've been wearing lately.
強かな佇まいの割に脆いソコに触れるの
Touching the fragile spot, despite your strong posture.
怒らないで darling！だってホントのことだもん
Don't be angry, darling! Because it's the truth, you know.
身体ばっかデカくなって中身はガキだよね
Your body has grown big, but you're still a kid inside.
暴れないで doggie！私華奢な手だから
Don't thrash about, doggie! Because I have delicate hands.
リードなんて気まぐれでパッと落としちゃうかも
I might just drop the leash on a whim.
だらし無い！意気地無い！ホント君は救えない！
Sloppy! Spineless! You really can't be saved!
堕落に耽っちゃってご愁傷様
Condolences for drowning in corruption.
夢が無い！糧も無い！くせに愛は欲しいの？
No dreams! No bread! Yet you want love?
なら3回まわってお手から…
Then spin three times and give me your paw...
るるるるってゅるるる
Ru-ru-ru-ru, tyu-ru-ru-ru
よく聞いて darling 僻み嫉み人の企み この世は罠だらけ
Listen closely, darling. Jealousy, envy, people's schemes, this world is full of traps.
ねぇ ずっとここにいて？ 跪いて doggie
Hey, will you stay here forever? Prostrate yourself, doggie.
生まれもった才と脳で全部を黙らせて 今日も稼いじゃう
Silencing everything with my inborn talent and brain, I'll keep earning today.
私の前に follow or die
In front of me, follow or die,
でも餌は気分次第 ねぇ ワタシを知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい？
but the food depends on my mood. Hey, do you want to go back to the days when you didn't know me?
walk into a trap 無知な babe 侵す drug
Walk into a trap, ignorant babe, consume drug.
もうワタシを知らなかった頃のキミは戻らない
You won't return to the days when you didn't know me anymore...
だらし無い、意気地無い、ホント君は救えない。
Sloppy, spineless, you really can't be saved.
どこにも行けないね
You can't go anywhere, can you?
くだらない！果てしない！こんな広い世界で
Boring! Endless! In such a wide world,
私に堕ちていく君が好き！
I love that you're falling for me!
夢が無い！糧も無い！くせに愛が欲しいの！
No dreams! No bread! Yet you want love!
なら3回まわってお手から
Then spin three times and give me your paw...
るるるるってゅるるる
Ru-ru-ru-ru, tyu-ru-ru-ru
お掛けになった電話番号は、現在使われておりません。
The number you have dialed is currently not in use.
意味わかんねぇ！
It don't even make sense!
どうせ誰も聞いてなんかいないさ
Anyway, nobody is really listening.
音楽なんてただのファッション
Music is just a fashion statement.
お行儀良くステージ退場 オンライン
Exiting the stage in an orderly manner, online.
どうせ何も伝えてなんかいないさ
Anyway, nothing is really being communicated.
レートがどうとか売名
Ratings and clout-chasing,
あいつ気取っておいて最低 グッナイ
he puts on airs, he's the worst. Good night.
どうしたってどうみたってどうしたってもう大渋滞
No matter what, no matter how you look at it, it's already a huge traffic jam.
それでもあっちこっちそっちこっち毎日Z世代それも欲しがる
Even so, here and there, every day, Gen Z wants that too.
パンチライン欲しいの？ 意味とかどっちだっていいよ
Do you want a punchline? Either meaning is fine.
歌詞とかどうでもいいので乗れるのをください
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something to groove to.
さあみんなで笑いましょう
Now, let's all laugh together.
芸術より数字の代償
The cost of numbers over art.
バイアスに酷い代償
A terrible price to bias.
じゃあどうすんの？
So what are we going to do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Is that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
Our heads spin in vain, dying out.
ふざけるな
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Bye-bye, viral melody.
歌えよ退化嘘ばかり
Sing! It's nothing but regression and lies.
バケモノ幻想でも理想でもいい
Monster, whether it's an illusion or an ideal, it's fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
嘘ばかりでもオーライ
Even if it's full of lies, it's alright.
嘘じゃないおカネや
It's not a lie, with money
理想で満たす前に
and ideals, before we fill it all up,
負けんな覚醒せよ子供たちよ
don't lose! Wake up, children!
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
意味はカンネー
I don't get the meaning!
お掛けになったそんな音楽は
The music you have dialed
現在使われておりません
is currently out of service.
ポップソングのヒットソング聴いて
Please listen to a hit pop song
もう一度お掛け直しください
and try dialing again.
あーもうハイカラサッカーバックスは臭いわ
Ah, seriously, high-collar Starbucks is disgusting.
あいつのあいつのあいつのあいつの 意味はカンネー
His, his, his, his... I don't get the meaning!
どうしたってどうみたってどうしたってもう大渋滞
No matter what, no matter how you look at it, it's already a huge traffic jam.
それでもあっちこっちそっちこっち毎日Z世代それも欲しがる
Even so, here and there, every day, Gen Z wants that too.
パンチライン欲しいの？ 意味とかどっちだっていいよ
Do you want a punchline? Either meaning is fine.
歌詞とかどうでもいいのでのびるのをください
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something that goes viral.
さあみんなで払いましょう
Now, let's all pay up.
芸術より数字なんでしょう
It's all about numbers over art, right?
バイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price to viralness.
じゃあどうすんの？
So what are we going to do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Is that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
Our heads spin in vain, dying out.
ふざけるな
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Bye-bye, viral melody.
歌えよ退化嘘ばかり
Sing! It's nothing but regression and lies.
バケモノ幻想でも理想でもいい
Monster, whether it's an illusion or an ideal, it's fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底終われない
We absolutely cannot end it like this.
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What we want is surely not money.
負けんな覚醒せよ子供たちよ
Don't lose! Wake up, children!
君の歌いたかったものが聴きたいんだ
I want to hear the thing you wanted to sing.
ふざけるな
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Bye-bye, viral melody.
歌えよ退化嘘ばかり
Sing! It's nothing but regression and lies.
バケモノ幻想でも理想でもいい
Monster, whether it's an illusion or an ideal, it's fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
嘘じゃないおカネや
It's not a lie, with money
理想で満たす前に
and ideals, before we fill it all up,
負けんな覚醒せよ子供たちよ
don't lose! Wake up, children!
僕の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing I wanted to sing?
意味はカンネー
I don't get the meaning!
せーの
Ready, set...
スバル先輩！
Subaru-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
何歳になったんだっけ？
How old did you turn again?
20歳バージョン2！
20 years old, version 2!
おおー！いいね！
Ooh! Nice!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ちょっとみんなせっかく来てくれた
Wait, everyone went through all this trouble...
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
あんた違うでしょ
Wait, you've got it wrong!
何番バージョン？
What version?
今日の主役ですから、みずみには！
Because Mizumi is today's main character!
で、ちょっとみんなに一言言ってね、去ってもらおうかなって
So, I thought I'd have everyone say a few words, and then have them leave!
一人ずつ来なさい。ほら。
Come one by one. Come on!
去る前にほら、一言言いに来なさい。ほら。
Before you leave, come say a quick word. Come on.
誰から？ほら。
Who's first? Come on.
嫌？うん。
No? Yeah...
ママだよ。
I'm your mommy.
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
もう、ほら、ちゃんと、次、次、次。
Geez, come on, next, next, next!
大丈夫っす。変な人いて怖かったでしょ？
It's okay. It was scary with that weird person, right?
ママよ。
I'm your mommy.
あ、違うよ。違う。違う。
Ah, that's wrong. Wrong. Wrong!
おかしいよ！
This is weird!
ちょっと待って、別に芸人のオーディションじゃなくて、芸人じゃないのよ。
Wait a second, this isn't some comedian audition! We're not comedians!
肩叩いてたからビビった。
You were patting my shoulder, so I got startled.
はい、これからもオリーお姉ちゃんに頼ってね。
Yes, continue to rely on big sister Ollie, okay?
お姉ちゃんと思ってんの？本当に。
Do you really think of her as a big sister?
おかしい！おかしい！
That's weird! That's weird!
ほら、ちゃんと、最後に、最後に、最後に、最後に...
Come on, for the last one, last one, last one, last one...
最後に、最後に...
For the last one, last one...
でも、うちらの、すぐそこの仲やんか。
But we're very close friends, aren't we?
だから、「せーの」って言ったら...
So, when I say "ready, set"...
分かるよな？
You get it, right?
イエス、イエス！
Yes, yes!
分かった！
Got it!
行くよ！せーの！スリー、ツー、ワン！
Here we go! Ready, set... Three, two, one!
待って！
Wait!
何で？
Why?
スリー、ツー、ワン、じゃない！
Not "Three, two, one"!
スリー、サイコー、だよ！
It's "Three, Saikou"!
あ、スリー、サイコー、ね！
Ah, "Three, Saikou"!
そう！せーの！
Yes! Ready, set...
スリー、サイコー！
Three, Saikou!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ハート作って、ハート作って！
Make a heart, make a heart!
これハート？
Is this a heart?
ハート、ハート、そうそうそう！
Heart, heart, yes, yes, yes!
大丈夫？
Is this okay?
届けるよ！
Deliver it!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうね、みんな！
Thank you, everyone!
ここで、バイバーイ！
Bye-bye from here!
コボも頑張って！
Kobo, do your best too!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ママ、ママ良かったよ！
Mama, Mama was great!
コボ、頑張ってね！
Kobo, do your best!
頑張れ、頑張れ！
Do your best, do your best!
バイバイ、バイバイ、頑張る、頑張る！
Bye-bye, bye-bye, I'll do my best!
なんか、うるさかったな。
They were kind of noisy.
頑張るか。
Alright, I'll do my best.
よし。
Okay.
くだらないアイの結末で
As the result of some trivial love,
僕らは生まれ落ちて
we were born into this world,
呼吸さえ強いられているけれど
and though we are even forced to breathe,
綺麗な言葉並べて
we line up pretty words,
醜さに蓋をして
put a lid on the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだな ずっと
and still remain unable to love ourselves, forever.
くだらない嘘を吐くたび
Every time we tell a trivial lie,
青色零れ落ちた
the color blue spills out.
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
Those glass-like eyes are beautiful,
君のその瞼のように
just like your eyelids,
優しい人になってさ
I want to become a kind person,
私の呼吸に終わりがあること
That my breath will one day come to an end,
君の声は覚えている
your voice remembers.
生まれては消えてゆくこと
Being born and fading away,
それだけを繰り返している
that is all we keep repeating.
僕らがもし また会えたらなんて 思ってた
I wondered if we could ever meet again.
生まれては消えてゆくだけの
Just being born and fading away,
青ずんだ波に名前をつけることに
did it make any sense to give names to these blue-bruised waves,
意味はなかったのかななんてさ
or was there no meaning after all?
他愛ない話が染みた
Our trivial conversations soaked in,
積み木で遊んでいる
playing with building blocks,
崩れるその日を待ってる
waiting for the day they collapse.
澄み切った夜の水際
At the water's edge on a clear night,
君の頬の明るさで
the brightness of your cheeks,
まもなく薄桜が咲くんだろう
soon, pale cherry blossoms will bloom.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても
Even if our breathing has no meaning,
二人はまた恋をする
the two of us will fall in love again.
生まれては消えてゆくこと
Being born and fading away,
それだけを繰り返している
that is all we keep repeating.
そして君も夜の海に帰ってゆくんだろう
And you too will probably return to the night sea.
生まれては消えてゆくだけの
Just being born and fading away,
青ずんだ波に名前をつけることに
by giving names to these blue-bruised waves,
囚われている項目
we are trapped.
覚えているかな
I wonder if you remember,
いつかの春の朝に
on that spring morning,
桜の木の下で 約束したこと
the promise we made under the cherry blossom tree.
思い出も君の名前も
Even memories and your name,
いつの日か失ってしまって
will someday be lost,
僕もいつかこの海と一つになるんだろう
and I too will eventually become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が
The winter air without you,
僕の頬を刺すその痛みさえ
stings my cheeks, and even that pain,
愛していたい
I want to cherish.
生まれては消えてゆくこと
Being born and fading away,
それだけを繰り返している
that is all we keep repeating.
僕らがもし また会えたらなんて 思ってた
I wondered if we could ever meet again.
生まれては消えてゆくだけの
Just being born and fading away,
青ずんだ波に名前をつけることに
did it make any sense to give names to these blue-bruised waves,
意味はなかったのかななんてさ
or was there no meaning after all?
unhappy?
悩める人の子よ
You troubled child of man,
unlucky?
人ならざる者も
And even those who are not human,
be happy!
弛まず目指せよ
Keep aiming for it without rest,
生きているんだし
after all, you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too.
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, good grief.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace!
unhappy?
unlucky?
be happy!
undead
ねえねえねえねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
somehow, for some reason, I feel like I'm fighting.
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch it, don't even want to touch it,
過去の自分自分自分自分と
my past self, self, self, self...
もうとっくに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost that's already long dead.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within childhood's painful memories,
残念 もう居ないのに
what a shame, even though they're no longer here.
あれ そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Oh? Is that one better? How ironic.
透かされてるのは現在の自分？ナンセンス
Is it my current self being seen through? Nonsense.
消えないレッテル
An indelible label.
yes!要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex.
取り憑かれてるみたい
It's like I'm possessed,
巻き付いたまま
tightly wrapped around me,
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
and still not letting go—my past self.
undead
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead, the chain of you and yourself.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to be happy is cowardly.
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting and encountering, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
But back to the point, peace, peace!
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
カットイン
Cut-in!
何だかどうして未来になんぞ何の希望もない期待出来ない
Somehow, for some reason, there's no hope, no expectation for the future...
ような気がして
That's how I feel.
もう随分生きている既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived long enough to be sick of clichés and déjà vu.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's no sign of anything wonderful.
残念
What a shame.
積んだ経験の因果形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
The karma of experience: hollowed myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I just want some excitement.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm bored of it, I've got used to it,
なんて
or so I say.
整っていくガイダンス増えるコンプライアンス
Perfecting guidance, increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
it feels like I'm being put under a lid.
吸い尽くして
Drinking it all up,
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
this, that, and everything tastes the same.
undead
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead, the chain of you and yourself.
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future are right here in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Simply live your life to the fullest,
目指せハッピーエンド
aim for a happy ending.
undead
死んじゃない お前に言っているんだ
I'm not dead, I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
Don't give up on your happiness, be human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it,
死んでいるも同然屍のアンデッド
is no different from being dead, a walking corpse.
unhappy?
悩める人の子よ
You troubled child of man,
unlucky?
人ならざる者も
And even those who are not human,
be happy!
弛まず目指せよ
Keep aiming for it without rest,
生きているんだろう
After all, you are alive, right?
不幸に浸るも
Whether you drown in unhappiness,
幸せになるのも
or choose to become happy,
そう全部全部お前だ
yes, it's all up to you.
古今東西
All times and places,
一切合切
everything,
森羅万象
all of creation,
ピースピース
peace, peace!
past & future
can't change the past
run for the future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Wherever people gather, there are always worries.
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Survive through this story filled only with monsters.
ちょこっとやんちゃで
A little mischievous,
にこっと元気な
with a cheerful smile,
ちらっとスマイル
a fleeting smile,
イントロ
intro.
毎日をもっと 楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun!
ドタバタなアドベンチャー
A slapstick adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even my fluttering skirt,
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it perfectly!
だからもっともっと 好きになってもいいよ保存
So, you can like me even more and more!
一緒に
Together,
大空に飛び立とう！
let's take off into the great blue sky!
光るスターライト
The shining starlight,
輝きの中で
within the radiance,
強いきらめき
a strong sparkle,
君に届いているかな
has it reached you yet?
1ミリでも
Even just one millimeter,
伝わればいいな
I hope it gets through!
チャージ完了！
Charge complete!
全速力アクセル
Full speed on the accelerator,
頑張る君へ
to you, who are doing your best!
一番乗りのスマイルを
Sending you my fastest smile!
君と ぷ・れ・あ・で・す！ ちゃんねる
With you on the Pleiades Channel!
Everyday 悩んで みんなで
Every day, with everyone worrying...
ブルーな気持ちに 唾を吐きかけ
Spit on your blue feelings,
お助けしちゃう ヒーロー
I'm a hero who will come to save you!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから
Because we can't stay weak-hearted,
つよつよで行きましょう
let's go strong and tough!
ハラハラな水着で
With thrilling swimsuits,
ドキドキのときめきタイム
it's a heart-pounding, exciting time!
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス
Come over anytime, it's a year-round paradise!
カウントダウン 曇り空吹き飛ばそう
Countdown! Let's blow away the cloudy skies!
上がれ! スターライト どんな暗闇の中も眩しく照らす
Rise up! Starlight, illuminating even the deepest darkness brilliantly.
君に見つけてもらえた それだけでもう
Just being found by you is already...
運命なんだ
...destiny.
もっとずっと 道は続いていくよ 夢に向かって
The road goes on much further, heading toward our dreams.
一緒に生きてくれるかな その手と手、走れ
Will you live this life together with me? Hand in hand, let's run!
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take you along, with everyone!
囁く 恥ずかしいけれど
Whispering is embarrassing, but...
伝えたい想い 今なら言える
these feelings I want to convey, I can say them now.
君のエールが 力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength!
いつも元気を 分けてくれて
Thank you for always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can keep doing my best and smile through the days, truly...
ありがとうの気持ちを歌えば
When we sing of our gratitude...
スターライト どんな輝きの中も強くきらめき
...Starlight, shining strongly through any brilliance,
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if just a fraction of it gets through, that's enough.
もっとずっと 道は続いていくよ 夢に向かって
The road goes on much further, heading toward our dreams.
一緒に生きてくれるかな その手と手、走れ
Will you live this life together with me? Hand in hand, let's run!
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take you along, with everyone!
君と ぷ・れ・あ・で・す！ ちゃんねる
With you on the Pleiades Channel!
スバル先輩ありがとうございました！家宝にします！
Thank you so much, Subaru-senpai! I'll treasure this!
おーちゃんがんばれー！お誕生日おめでとー！
Go for it, O-chan! Happy birthday!
誰かのための痛み？
Pain for someone else's sake?
僕の願い、やがて散り散り
My wishes will eventually scatter.
椅子取りゲームみたい
It's like musical chairs,
それでも、息をしていくしかない
but still, I have no choice but to breathe.
まだ、聞こえるか？
Can you still hear it?
とっくのとうに詰まった呼吸
My breath has long been clogged.
関係ない、うるせえわ
Irrelevant, shut up.
自分だけ超えてる
I'm the only one surpassing it.
安定なんて捨てた
I've thrown away stability,
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
already at a speed that shakes off everything.
その瞬間まで、足掻いて
Struggling until that moment,
ただ、脳絞って今、見えるとこまで
just squeezing my brain to what I can see now.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drinking all of this moment and dancing again,
見たことないもの、見せて
show me what I've never seen before.
「君の代わりはいない」
"There's no replacement for you,"
もし、誰かが否定しても
even if someone denies it.
僕の代わりはいない
There's no replacement for me,
違うことない、僕の目覚まし
no mistake, it's my awakening!
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み
The pain of brushing off someone's praying hand,
さあ、この瞬間を飲み干して
Now, drink up this moment,
また踊って
and dance again,
見たことないもの見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
連れて行かれるように
As if being taken away,
踏み出した暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark streets.
Tell me what you need
後追う背中は黒く染まってた
The back I followed was dyed black.
Wait, hold up
悪党？それとも正義？
A villain? Or justice?
やりがい searching 馬鹿みたい
Searching for worth is like a fool.
目の前の問題は it's too much now
The problem before me is too much now.
後回しでもまあ良いじゃん
It's fine to just put it off, right?
人生の意味 結局何？
What's the meaning of life in the end?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
A voice cracking in these unstable days.
あれこれ言ってる間に
While fussing over this and that,
姿消し去った君は誰？
who are you, who disappeared?
曖昧な世界が変わった
The ambiguous world has changed
あの日
on that day...
ど派手に響かせた声がまた
The voice that resonated so flashily
今も鳴り止まない
still hasn't stopped ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
増えていく影を追い
Chasing the growing shadows,
気づけば遠い街で
before I knew it, I was in a distant town.
引き返し元通りになるのには
To turn back and return to how it was...
もう遅かった
it was already too late.
Wait, hold up now
SOS 逃げ道がないの
SOS, there is no way out.
え、ちょっ、待って
Wait, what?
How is it my fault?
レフト ライト
Left, right...
ステップからの
from the step...
get down に見せかけて clap
pretending to get down, clap.
からかっていて立場は対等？
Teasing me, are we on equal footing?
助けてやって何その態度
What's with that attitude after I helped you?
不満の中で生まれる依存症
An addiction born from dissatisfaction.
垣間見えるのは愛
Glimpses of love...
退屈な世界が変わった
The boring world has changed
あの日
on that day...
ど派手に響かせた声がまた
The voice that resonated so flashily
今も鳴り止まない
still hasn't stopped ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
Oh yeah
このどうしようもない感情に
In this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
はい はい 腹から声出して
Yes, yes, shout from your gut.
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Otherwise, you'll learn the hard way.
勝敗かけた歌合戦
A singing battle with victory on the line,
枯れそうな地声で
with a cracking natural voice...
まだ歌うのさ
I'll keep on singing!
ど派手に響かせた声がまた
The voice that resonated so flashily
今も鳴り止まない
still hasn't stopped ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
no no no no no
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
関係 探って
Searching for a connection...
あ、ごめんね
Ah, I'm sorry.
って意味がないね
But that's meaningless, isn't it?
バグだらけ 有る事無い事
Full of bugs, things true or false...
満ち足りない？
Not satisfied yet?
じゃあ どうなりたい？
Then, what do you want to be?
そっと暴いて
Gently exposing...
二重で被る面相
the double-layered mask.
優しい言葉並べて
Lining up kind words,
ふたりお揃いに甘えて
we both indulge in this matching sweetness.
演じて魅せてるのは誰の為？
For whose sake are we putting on this act?
ただ泣いたように笑っていたんだ
I was just smiling as if I had cried.
All eyes on me 偽りの Deepfaker
All eyes on me, a fake Deepfaker.
I なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't even understand "I".
All eyes on me いつの間にか Deepfaker
All eyes on me, a Deepfaker before I knew it.
重ね重ねお詫びします 気持ちのない口癖
Apologizing repeatedly with a half-hearted habit,
優しさにズルさも吐き違えて
mistaking kindness for slyness...
重ね、重ねた嘘の吐息だけで満たされるマスク
A mask filled only with repeated sighs of lies,
まだ二重で縛っている 心の中
still doubly bound inside my heart.
さんざん取り繕っている
Constantly patching things up...
本当の顔は 誰のためで
For whose sake is the true face?
だんだん苦しくなるね
Gradually, it becomes painful,
お揃いの甘えの前まえ、の前、の前
leaning on each other, imitating it...
ただ泣いていないで 笑っていたいよう
I just want to laugh, not cry.
all eyes on me いつまでも feel flavor
All eyes on me, forever feel flavor.
i なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand the "I".
all eyes on me いつの日にか deepfaker
All eyes on me, someday, a deepfaker.
脱いでみたい
I want to try taking it off.
演技でもないなら
If it's not acting...
それまで肩寄せながら
...until then, leaning on each other,
胸に秘めている deepfaker
with a deepfaker hidden in the heart.
まだ泣いたように 笑っていたんだ
Still, like crying, I was smiling.
all eyes on me 偽りの deepfaker
All eyes on me, a deceptive deepfaker.
i なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand the "I".
all eyes on me いつのまにか deepfaker
All eyes on me, unconsciously becoming a deepfaker.
all eyes, all eyes, all eyes on me, on me, on me, deepfaker
all eyes, all eyes, all eyes on me, deep, deep, deep, deep, deepfaker
はぁ、はぁ、はぁ...
Haa, haa...
みんな、どうでしたか？
Everyone, how was it?
いや、今回はですね、あの、ハウスに初めて挑戦したんですけれども、
Well, this time, I tried house dancing for the first time,
あの、2ヶ月で、あの、詰め込んで、踊れてましたか？
putting it all together in just two months. Did I manage to dance it well?
いやー、「めっちゃ頑張った」ってコメントが書いてくれてるんだろうなぁ！
I bet you guys are leaving comments like, "You did your absolute best!"
いやはや。でね、あの、「波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること」って曲では、
Right? And in the song "Naming the Waves, Our Breaths Having an End,"...
リフトしたり、あの、クルクルね、回って、あれも初めてやりました！
...we did lifts and spun around, which was also my first time trying those!
踊れてたら嬉しいね！
I hope I danced it well!
いや、ゲストのね、ハコス先輩、ハジたんとイケイケに踊って、
I danced so energetically with my guests, Hakos-senpai and Hajitan,
スバル先輩とは、憧れのスバル先輩と二人きりでドキドキタイムしちゃったり、
and I had a heart-pounding moment alone with the Subaru-senpai whom I admire,
ラプラス、ルイ先輩と、らでんちゃんとはね、対決しまくって、
and battled a lot with Laplus, Lui-senpai, and Raden-chan,
ロボ子先輩とマリンちゃんは勝って、AZKiとはカッコよく、いや、
won against Roboco-senpai and Marine-chan, and performed coolly with AZKi! Well...
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか！
There were so many wonderful guest parts, weren't there?
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか？
So, everyone, aren't you forgetting something?
ね、皆さん、ちょっと水見や、休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Hey, everyone... my break time has to end pretty soon.
よし、立つか！
Alright, time to stand up!
うわー！はい、ということで、なんとですね、
Whoa! Okay, so... actually,
こんな感じで言うのも何ですが、新曲が出ます！
it's a bit sudden to announce like this, but I'm releasing a new song!
イェーイ！初の！オリジナル楽曲！
Yay! My very first original song!
あ、やばい、体が疲れれた、よらしょ、よらしょ。
Ah, oh no, my body is so tired. Up we go...
はい、ということで、えっと、作詞・作曲・編曲はサトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
So, the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were done by Yuuri Satoda!
ありがとう、ドンドコパフパフドンドコパフパフ！
Thank you so much!
はい、このあと、すぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わったあとあるのです。が、リダイレクトで飛びます。
And right after this stream ends, the MV will be premiered! You will be automatically redirected to it.
そして、デジタルリリースは今日の0時からなので、たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
Also, the digital release starts at midnight tonight, so I hope you listen to it a lot!
じゃ、ちょっと早速なんですけど、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな！
Now, without further ado, let's perform this new song!
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう、気になるなー、どんな楽曲なんだろう、行きます！
I wonder what kind of song it is! I'm so excited! Here we go!
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ
Umya-unya, umya-unya
うにゃうにゃ うにゃうにゃ
Unya-unya, unya-unya
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ
Umya-unya, umya-unya
うにゃうにゃ うにゃうにゃ
Unya-unya, unya-unya
きゅるるん きゅるるん あ〜そろそろご飯の時間かな？
Kyururun, kyururun! Ah, is it about time for a meal?
あ でもでも、やっぱやっぱ 家から一歩も出たくな〜い
Ah, but still, I really don't wanna step a single foot outside!
こんな時はそうだ！ 飯テロの動画！
In times like this, that's it! Food porn videos!
「説明しよう！ 極限までお腹を空かし美味しくいただくのだ！」
"Let me explain! You starve yourself to the absolute limit to make it taste delicious!"
めんどい めんどい マジめんどい わ
So annoying, so annoying, it's seriously such a pain!
けっきょくぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
In the end, I just slacked off and melted my time away!
ぴろりん ぴろりん 5回目のアラーム
Ring-ring, ring-ring, my fifth alarm...
コンビニいこ！
Let's go to the convenience store!
わちゃわちゃ はちゃめちゃ 奇想天外
Rowdy, chaotic, and completely unpredictable!
ドタバタ てんやわんや 見逃せない
Hectic, topsy-turvy, don't miss a single beat!
ピンチだってちょいのちょいのちょいで
Even a crisis is a piece of cake!
てゃっ！ てゃっ！ そりゃっ！ そりゃっ！ 万事解決☆
Yah! Yah! Take that! Take that! All problems solved!
ラッキー！
Lucky!
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ 美味しくな〜れ
Umya-unya, umya-unya, turn into something delicious!
あれも これも 全部 食べた 食べた〜い （ちょうだい！）
I wanna eat this, and that, and absolutely everything! (Gimme!)
ぱくぱく うみゃうにゃ ハピネスライフ
Munch munch, umya-unya, a happy life!
食べて寝て遊んで また食べる （おーいぇー！）
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again! (Oh yeah!)
ペコペコ ペコペコ はらぺこじゃ （おかわり！）
Tummy rumbling, tummy rumbling, I'm starving! (Seconds, please!)
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ 食いきません？
Umya-unya, umya-unya, can't finish it?
ひとまずご飯を お腹いっぱい
For now, let's fill our bellies with food!
食べさせてよ
Let me eat up!
うみゃうにゃ
Umya-unya!
うにゃうにゃ
Unya-unya?
うみゃうにゃ
Umya-unya!
あ～、いい天気～ あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
Ah, what nice weather... That cloud looks like soft-serve ice cream!
あ、あっちはわたがし！
Ah, that one over there is cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう…
Clouds are so fluffy and look delicious...
人生で1回は食べてみたいよね～
I'd love to try eating them once in my life!
じゃない！！
Wait, no!
しんどいしんどいまじしんどいわ
It's tiring, it's tiring, it's really tiring.
現実逃避何度ももしちゃうわ
I escape from reality over and over again.
妄想空想頭が暴走
Delusions, daydreams, my head is running wild.
カツオ食べたーい！！！
I want to eat bonito!
だらだらぐうたら怠惰全開
Lounging around, totally lazy.
ネガティブ思考もご愛嬌です！
Negative thoughts are just part of my charm!
世界だってぽいぽいのぽいで
I'll toss the world away just like that,
えいやっ！えいやっ！どりゃっ！どりゃっ！
Ei-ya! Ei-ya! Dorya! Dorya!
ねじ伏せちゃうぞ☆
And force it into submission!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃ お腹空いたら
Umya-umya-umya-umya, when I get hungry,
突撃となりの晩ごはん
I'll raid the neighbor's dinner!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃしあわせタイム
Chomp, chomp, umya-umya, happy time.
主に食欲で生きてます
I mostly live on my appetite.
だからどうかお願い
So please, I beg of you,
このおなかを満たして神様
Fill this stomach of mine, O God!
たべたーい
I want to eat!
ねてたーい
I want to sleep!
むずかしいことは何も考えたくない
I don't want to think about anything difficult.
「あとあと、みんなでお菓子パーティもしたーい！！」
"And also, I want to have a sweets party with everyone!"
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃ おいしくなぁれ☆
Umya-umya-umya-umya, become delicious☆
あれもこれもぜんぶ食べたいの
I want to eat this, that, and everything!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Chomp, chomp, umya-umya, happiness life.
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べ
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again.
ぺこぺこぺこぺこはらぺこじゃ
I'm super, super hungry!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃ 食いしん坊
Umya-umya-umya-umya, I'm a glutton!
ひとまずごはんをお腹いっぱい
For now, let me eat my fill of food...
食べさせて！
Let me eat!
まだ足りない
It's still not enough!
もっともっと食べさせて
Let me eat more and more!
新曲、どうだったー？かわいかったでしょー？
How was the new song? It was cute, right?
「かわいい」っていうコメントがたくさん見えます！ありがとね！かわいいかわいい、ありがとう！知ってる知ってる！
I see so many comments saying "cute"! Thank you! Thank you for the "cute, cute"! I know, I know!
ということでね、新曲のタイトルは「うみゃうにゃはっぴーらいふ」でしたー！
So, the title of the new song was "Umyaunya Happy Life"!
今回はちょっとかわいい感じにしたので、次はなんかかっこいい感じにしたいなー、みたいな。ま、何も決まってないんですけどね！
Since I went with a cute vibe this time, next time I want to do something cool. Well, nothing's decided yet, though!
ということで、新曲が終わったからって、帰ろうとしてない？ねぇ、何か忘れてるよね、みんな？と、いうことで、グッズ！
So, just because the new song is over, you aren't trying to leave, are you? Hey, you're forgetting something, right, everyone? And with that, merchandise!
水宮枢、誕生日記念2026のグッズをさっそく1つずつ見ていこう！
Let's take a look at Mizumiya Su's Birthday Celebration 2026 merch one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First up, this!
オーロラアクリルパネル！公式イラストレーターのぶくろてママに描いてもらいました！ありがとママ！
The Aurora Acrylic Panel! It was illustrated by my official illustrator, Bukurote-mama! Thank you, Mama!
ふわふわのね、お部屋でお茶会みたいなね、かわいい感じになっております！もうママが天才すぎるのでぜひ買ってください！
It has a cute look, like having a tea party in a fluffy room! Mama is just too much of a genius, so please buy it!
2つ目は、こちら！
Second is this!
ハート型缶バッジ！ハートハートハートハート！
Heart-shaped can badges! Heart, heart, heart, heart!
こちらはね、もう可愛いお顔がドアップになってます。多分、ハート型の缶バッジは初めてなんじゃないかなと思っているので、ぜひこちらも買ってみてください！
This features a close-up of my cute face. I think this might be my first heart-shaped can badge, so please try buying this too!
3つ目が、こちら！
Third is this!
おくるみすうぬいぐるみ！
Swaddled Su Plushie!
こちらもね、すうちゃんがおくるみに入っています！まぁなんか、すうをね、結構おくるみに入れてくれてる方も見たりとかしたので、
This one has Su-chan in a swaddle blanket! I've seen some of you put Su in swaddles, so...
もしかしたらみんなこういうのを待っていたんじゃないかなと思って作りました！衣装はね、キービジュアルの衣装で、ちょっと小さめのぬいぐるみを作ってみました！
I thought you might have been waiting for something like this, so I made it! The outfit is from the key visual, and I made it a slightly smaller plushie!
4つ目は、こちら！
Fourth is this!
れきお一推しショルダーバッグ！
Rekio's Most Recommended Shoulder Bag!
こちらにですね、さっきのハート型のね、缶バッジとかおくるみぬいぐるみがいれられるようになってます！はい、天才！天才！天才！
In this, you can put the heart-shaped can badges and swaddled plushie we just saw! Yes, genius! Genius! Genius!
ということで、こちらも一緒にぜひ、れきおのね、推し活のバッグにいれて、すうをね、あの、可愛く持ってください！よろしくね！他の推しもぜひ入れてみてね！
So, please put them in Rekio's fan-activity bag together and carry Su around cutely! Thank you! Feel free to put your other favorites in too!
5つ目が、こちら！
Fifth is this!
ボイス！タイトルは「すうとお茶会」！
Voice pack! The title is "Tea Party with Su"!
こちらはね、お家で優雅な、優雅な、優雅なアフタヌーンティーを楽しむすうと一緒にね、いっぱい楽しんじゃおうボイスとなっております！
This is a voice pack where you can enjoy an elegant, elegant, elegant afternoon tea at home with Su and have lots of fun together!
最後に、フルセット！
Lastly, the full set!
直筆サイン入りのオリジナルカードと、ASMRボイスがついてきます！ちょっとね、すうちゃんの…
It comes with an autographed original card and ASMR voice! Now, Su-chan's...
おうちに、お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね
Everyone who gets invited to my house...
ちょっと距離近めでね
...will be a little bit closer.
ASMRボイスが
The bonus ASMR voice...
こんな感じで。まあ適当なんですけど、そんな感じのボイスになっております！
...is like this! Well, that was just a random example, but it's a voice like that!
こちら、数量限定じゃ、ない！
This is NOT limited in quantity!
ので、焦らずに、みんなゆっくりで大丈夫です
So there's no need to rush, you can take your time.
グッズは、22時10…ん？
The merchandise will go on sale at 22:10... Huh?
22時10分から販売開始です
Yes, it goes on sale at 22:10!
直筆のサインとかもね、もう全部、何もかも数量限定じゃないので
Even the handwritten signature full set is not limited in quantity.
あの、すうちゃんのサインもあの、ついてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら
Suzu's signature will be included if you buy the full set!
みなさん、よろしくお願いします。ぜひ！
So everyone, please check it out. Definitely!
買ってね！
Please buy it!
いっぱい買ってね！
Buy lots of them!
はい！ということで、以上、みにみやによるグッズ紹介でした！
Yes! So, that was the merchandise introduction by Mini-Miya!
うわあ！
Whoa!
はーい、ということで、みにみやありがとう！
Alright, thank you, Mini-Miya!
なんか結構ミスってたな。まあ、みにみやだからね
She seemed to make quite a few mistakes, but she is Mini-Miya, after all.
まあ、すうじゃないから。まあ仕方ないか。仕方ないか！
She isn't Suzu, so I guess it can't be helped. It can't be helped!
ということで、誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうか！
So, how did you like my birthday 3D live concert?!
憧れのホロライブに入ってから、みんなにいっぱい応援してもらって
Since joining my dream Hololive, everyone has supported me so much...
ここまで来れました
...and that's how I was able to get this far.
みんなに少しでもね、「かっこよかった」とか
I would be so happy if even a little bit of you thought I was cool...
「すうちゃんのこと応援しててよかった」って思ってもらえると、とっても嬉しいです
...or felt glad that you've supported Suzu.
MVはこのあとすぐ公開で、リダイレクトで飛ぶので
The music video will be released right after this, and you'll be redirected there.
チャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
So please stay tuned and keep your eyes on this channel!
ということで、みんな、これからもよろしくね！ありがとう！
So, everyone, please continue to support me! Thank you!
じゃあ、ばいばーい！またねー！
Well then, bye-bye! See you later!
すうりすへ
すうを見つけて、応援してくれてありがとう！
[Text] To Suurisu,
Thank you for finding Suzu and supporting me!
そのおかげでみんなにこれからも
かけがえのない、じまんのおしになれるよ！
[Text] Thanks to that, I can continue to be
your irreplaceable, proud favorite!
これからもコツコツがんばっていくので
おうえんしてね！
[Text] I will keep working hard step by step,
so please continue to support me!
すうががんばれるのは すうりすのおかげ！！
[Text] The reason Suzu can do her best
is all thanks to Suurisu!!